(MUSIC PLAYING)
KARA: OTL Releasing
presents
a BH Production
and Goldpost Pictures
production,
in association
with Automatik Entertainment,
Nervous Tick
and Film Victoria.
Upgrade.
(MUFFLED SONG PLAYING)
(BLUES SONG PLAYING ON RECORD)
(CLATTERING SOUNDS)
(GREY SINGING ALONG)
(CLATTERING SOUND CONTINUES)
(CRANKING)
(THUDS)
(MUSIC STOPS)
Okay, come on.
(ENGINE STARTS)
(ENGINE REVVING)
(ENGINE STOPS)
I love you.
(BOTTLES CLINKING)
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
HANDLEY: You can't be
an idealist
and a capitalist, Asha.
You gotta pick a side.
I think I can.
No, you can't.
I'm telling you...
KARA: Arriving at your
house, Asha.
Saved by my car.
Goodbye, Handley.
(GASPS) Oh, my God!
KARA: Are you okay, Asha?
I'm fine.
The husband scared me.
(ASHA CHUCKLES)
You do realize that you're
talking to a car, right?
I hear you talking
to yours all the time.
At least mine
can talk back.
(CHUCKLES)
Oh, working hard I see.
(LAUGHS)
KARA: Welcome home, Asha.
Evening playlist one.
The temperature indoors
is 72 degrees...
(MUSIC PLAYING)
...and the energy wall
is charged at 86%.
Also, you've run out of eggs.
Thanks, Kara. Order them.
Actually, I was
working very hard today.
In fact, that right there
is the celebratory beer.
Is that right?
GREY: Yeah.
I dropped the block
in the Firebird today.
Finished her up.
You wanna see?
I have no idea
what you just said.
Okay, well, I don't know what
you do for a living either,
wife, so we're even.
Yes, but is staying home
all day playing with cars
a living, Grey?
I don't know. Dunno.
Ow!
(GIGGLES)
That hurt. It hurt good.
You know what?
I'm actually getting kind of
used to you wearing
the pants in this household.
Really?
Yeah.
I'm really settling in.
Stop it.
Well, you know
I'm never giving
them back, so...
Bet you 10 bucks
I can get them off.
No, stop! (LAUGHS)
You want to print a pizza?
You wanna make a pizza?
(EXCLAIMS) Sounds
like a lot of work.
Oh, I got to drop
the car off to this guy
tonight. It's all done.
(GROANS)
Okay, well, have fun.
What do you mean, have fun?
You're coming with me.
What?
Yeah. (CHUCKLES)
I need you to drive me home
in that toy car of yours.
It's like 45 minutes away.
I'll push a button
and end up in
Canada or something.
Well, I have work to do,
so I can't.
Can't lives on
won't street, lady.
You're coming with me
and believe me, you're gonna
wanna see this guy's house.
Trust me.
(OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING)
(DRONES HOVERING)
(CAR HUMMING)
(REVVING)
(BIRDS CAWING)
(ENGINE SPUTTERS)
(WIND BLOWING)
So, what, he lives
behind the rocks?
No, just you wait.
(CHUCKLES)
Really?
Oh, yeah, really.
After you.
(WHISPERS) What?
(BIRDS SCREECHING)
(ASHA CHUCKLES)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
This is amazing.
GREY: Eron, my man.
(THUNDER RUMBLES)
I got the Firebird
upstairs, ready to go.
You're early.
Yeah, I, uh...
I drive fast. (STUTTERS)
What is the thing
that you're touching?
It's my cloud.
Eron,
I'd like you to meet
my wife, Asha.
Hi. Nice to meet you.
Uh, yes. Hello.
Hi.
Wait, you're Eron Keen?
You own Vessel Computers.
Oh, my God.
Husband did not tell me
who I was meeting. I...
I really love your company.
You do the most
incredible things.
I'm in the industry, too.
I work for, um, Cobolt.
We specialize in robotic limbs
for wounded soldiers.
I mean, we're nothing like
Vessel yet, but we're
getting there.
No, you're not.
(CHUCKLES)
ERON: I'll show you why.
Follow me.
I would like
to introduce you
to my present,
and the rest
of the world's future.
I call it "Stem."
GREY: Wow!
That is the most
incredible
little roach.
What does it do?
Literally anything.
Huh.
It can drive anything,
talk to anything,
calculate anything.
It's a new, better brain.
Can it make babies
and play football?
It can do things
that'll benefit society.
Okay, you know
what he means.
I'm just saying, there's
some things that people
do better.
I mean,
you look at that widget
and you see the future,
and I look at that thing,
I see 10 guys on an
unemployment line.
You should try not to argue
with that guy. He's your
last paying customer.
(CHIMES)
KARA: Please do not touch
the steering wheel
while the car is in motion.
(CHUCKLING)
Okay, so what's a guy like me
supposed to do when
his widget starts taking over
the world?
Hmm?
Sit back and enjoy
the ride? Come here.
You know, there are
some benefits not having
to keep your eyes
on the road.
Oh, yeah?
Mmm-hmm.
What should I
keep my eyes on?
(GIGGLES)
Mmm.
KARA: Please put
your seatbelts on.
No fun.
Mmm.
KARA: Leaving 601 freeway.
(DEVICE TRILLING)
Wait, honey, where are we?
ASHA: She's probably
just taking us
around the traffic.
Wait, no. No, wait.
I'm sorry, this is...
No, this is my
old neighborhood.
This is where I grew up.
Yeah, this is New Crown.
I mean, we're going
in the exact opposite
direction of the house.
Kara, take us home.
KARA: I'm sorry,
there has been an error.
Return to the freeway.
Destination home.
I'm sorry,
there has been an error.
What?
Uh, stop. Car. Car. Stop.
Press the brake twice.
Turning left.
(TIRES SCREECHING)
God damn it!
God damn it, stop.
Let me try this.
We're going
a little too fast.
This is not
supposed to be...
Shit!
(CAR SCRAPING)
(DEVICES TRILLING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
KARA: There has been
an accident.
(PANTING)
Please remain seated
until further instructions.
Emergency services
have been contacted.
(PANTING)
Grey!
Here to help.
Babe?
(ASHA GRUNTS)
(PANTING)
Will you get us...
(GROANS)
(WHIMPERS)
Back up! Back up!
Stay right there,
partner.
We're on TV,
assholes. Hurry!
(BEEPING)
(INDISTINCT RADIO CHATTER)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Hey, what are you doing?
Put your mask back on!
Look, you guys, you can have
my wallet. Take our cards,
okay? You can have it all.
TOLAN: (LAUGHS)
Thanks for your permission.
Don't you fucking
touch her! (GRUNTS)
You look at me and see
a real piece of shit
on your shoe, don't you?
(WHIMPERS)
A learned woman
like yourself,
looking down on
an uneducated
insect like me.
(GUN COCKS)
(GUNSHOT)
(ASHA WHEEZING)
No! No!
No!
POLICE DRONE: (ON RADIO)
Four hostiles, two prone.
(SCREAMS)
GREY: Asha!
(GUN POWERING, FIRES)
Asha...
(WHIMPERING)
(GASPING)
FISK: Till death do us part.
Asha. I can't get to you.
I can't move.
Asha.
Stay with me, okay?
Look at me, honey.
(SHUDDERING)
Okay, I'm right here.
I'm right here, okay, Ash?
I'm right here.
No, no, Asha.
Asha, no, please...
(OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING)
(SIREN WAILING)
(INDISTINCT RADIO CHATTER)
(OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING)
(INAUDIBLE)
(ASSISTED BREATHING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
NURSE HENDERSON: I mean,
everything that's installed
just allows you to live a more
normal life.
These robotic arms
are fully capable of
preparing meals for you.
Let's say you wanted
a protein shake.
You would just say
"protein shake."
Your mother also has
voice control authority
over the arms.
Would you like to do
the honors, Pam?
(PAMELA CHUCKLES)
Sure.
Um, protein shake.
Oh, my Lord!
(CHUCKLES)
Oh! (CHUCKLES)
NURSE HENDERSON:
There you go.
I think we'll be
fine from here.
Okay.
I'll walk you out.
Oh, thank you.
(DOOR CLOSES)
KARA: Charging now complete.
Are you there, Grey?
Would you like something?
May I ask if Asha
will be joining us for dinner?
(WATER FLOWING)
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
You know, you
don't have to stay here
day and night, Mom.
You know, these machines
they installed pretty much
do everything for me.
I know.
(VOMITS)
PAMELA:
It's okay. It's okay.
That's it,
that's it, that's it.
(COUGHING)
(SOBBING)
(SNIFFLES)
(SIRENS WAILING)
(INDISTINCT RADIO CHATTER)
(INDISTINCT LAUGHTER
AND CHATTER)
PAMELA: Detective Cortez.
Hi, Pam. Hi, Grey.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
All right, this is me.
Here, you can
have a seat here.
Thanks.
You know,
I'm from New Crown,
Grey. Like you.
Went to Hellier High.
So what do you have?
Okay.
I know you were anxious
to come down here
and see how we're
getting things done,
and I think that's great.
I'm a face-to-face person
myself, you know.
I don't pilot these drones.
I like to get
my hands dirty.
Bang on doors...
So who are these guys?
We don't know yet.
I do have a list of people
of interest in that area,
and just this week
I brought in two people
for questioning.
So what you're saying is
you have all these things
flying above our heads
that can read the ID chips
in our fillings but don't
actually do anything.
No. I mean, yes, they work.
But it's not that simple.
Criminals can find
ways around them.
If they can find
the right people,
criminals can get a firewall
built around them
that prevents our drones
from identifying their faces.
Believe me, I understand
your frustration, I do...
I know I can't tie
my shoes anymore, Detective,
but you don't have
to talk to me like
I'm a goddamn 3-year-old.
Grey, she's just
trying to help.
I'm gonna work
through my list,
and if you wanna
work with me,
we're gonna find them.
How can I work with you?
I can't even stand.
Administer PM medicine.
Problem.
Again.
Administer PM medicine.
Problem. Again!
Again.
KARA: I cannot administer
any more medication, Grey.
No, you didn't do it right.
You didn't do it right.
Administer PM medicine.
Another dosage
could be fatal.
I will contact an ambulance
to transport you to a hospital
if you are in serious pain.
(MONITOR BEEPING STEADILY)
I'm not gonna
give you bird flu, kid.
I don't leave my
house very often.
Must be
frustrating for you.
You're someone
who liked to get things
done with their hands.
Now you can't.
I'm sorry, was that
inappropriate?
I'm not around
enough people
to know the difference.
Okay, here's the difference.
What the fuck
do you want, Eron?
(INDISTINCT ANNOUNCEMENT
ON PA)
Grey.
What if I told you
I could offer you something
that would enable you
to walk again?
That computer chip
that I showed you.
It has the potential to change
everything for people
in your condition.
As a quadriplegic,
the line connecting
your brain to your
limbs has been cut.
Stem would
bridge that gap.
The operation would
take place in my home,
away from official eyes.
So there'd be
no more hospitals.
But it would
have to be our secret.
For now.
Here's the thing, kid.
I'm not looking
to restart my life.
I'm looking
for the off switch.
You know,
you were right
about them.
Computers.
There are things
that they can't do.
They can't bring
her back, Grey.
But they just might be able
to bring you back.
What would she want?
(MONITOR CONTINUES BEEPING)
(EERIE MUSIC PLAYING)
ERON: This is a world first.
Never before has
a biomechanical fusion
been asked to do so much.
It's going to feel
strange initially.
The neural pathways
in your brain will be
trying to have a conversation
with a foreign body.
Trying to learn
to pass the baton.
The key is to let it
grow into itself.
(STAPLING)
DR. GORDON: Grey,
can you hear me?
(GASPS SOFTLY)
Can you feel it
when I do this?
My guess is
this is going to be
a piecemeal process.
You shouldn't be expecting
unreasonable results so soon.
Oh, my God.
Now try to stand.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(WHEELCHAIR RATTLES)
ERON: Nobody can know.
They make people like me
wait years to test
something like this.
But I can't
wait for them.
Signing confidentiality
agreements is never fun,
but I bet it will feel
good to do it with
your own hand.
Who's moving my arms
and my legs?
Me or your widget?
You're the one
doing it all.
You're not a robot.
Stem works in service
of your brain.
Your brain gives
Stem a command.
He makes it happen.
Close door.
(WATER DRIPPING)
(DOOR CLOSES)
KARA: Good evening, Grey.
Another package from
Detective Cortez
has been delivered.
Would you like...
Shut up.
Did you say, "Shut down"?
Yeah, I did. Shut down.
STEM: May I
point something out?
Hello?
Yes?
Okay, who's saying that?
I am Stem,
the system operating
your body for you.
Don't be afraid.
You fucking kidding me?
No.
I've gone insane.
I'm fucking insane.
Your psychological report
diagnosed you with mild
PTSD symptoms,
but you are not insane.
Wait, so, okay, you've been
sitting there this whole time
since the operation?
I've been observing
everything you've observed.
Do you have to talk?
If you don't want
me to, I will not.
Okay, yeah, don't talk.
(WATER DRIPPING)
So I'm not insane?
You can talk again.
STEM: No,
you are not insane.
Wait, can anybody
else hear you?
No, only you.
I'm sending sound waves
to your eardrum.
Can you read my mind?
No.
I can only discern speech
when you talk out loud.
Now that you've allowed me
to talk again, may I
point something out?
In the drone
surveillance footage.
Can't you see it?
See what?
The man who shot your wife.
There's no gun in his hand.
She was shot. That
means he had a gun.
She was shot,
but not with a gun he
was holding in his hand.
A gun implanted
inside his hand.
Freeze the screen
at the moment he fires.
The man who took Asha's purse.
In the left of frame.
There is a marking
on his wrist.
I don't see it.
I do. I've rebuilt the image.
With your permission,
I can show you.
Just relax and let me draw.
(SCRIBBLING)
GREY: This feels very weird.
STEM: You now have
full control again, Grey.
I've seen these.
It's a military
tattoo, I think.
I will read it.
Hold it in front
of your eye.
Serk Brantner. Marine Corps.
098-422. O-Positive. Catholic.
Address, 414 Citrus,
New Crown.
(MUTTERS)
You just found this guy.
I got you,
you sons of bitches.
Call Detective Cortez.
(PHONE BEEPS AND LINE RINGS)
STEM: Are you sure you want
to call Detective Cortez?
Yes, I am sure.
You just found the guy
who murdered my wife.
Do you have evidence
to prove that?
(PHONE LINE RINGING)
End call.
You saw the tattoo.
Eron has forbidden you
to tell anyone about me.
Okay, maybe
I drew it from memory.
My reconstruction
of the tattoo
does not provide
any real evidence,
unless they can correlate it
exactly with the drone video,
which they can't.
What are you saying?
You need to be positive
it's him before you
alert the police.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(BIRDS FLUTTERING)
(CAR BEEPS)
(ENGINE STARTS)
(TIRES SCREECHES)
(DRONE HOVERING)
Lock chair.
(CHAIR BEEPS AND LOCKS)
(DOG BARKING)
STEM: There are
no alarms inside,
but it is a manual lock.
I can't help you break it.
GREY: Don't worry, I got this.
(DOOR UNLOCKS)
(DOOR CREAKING)
STEM: I suggest you
remove your shoes.
(DOG CONTINUES
BARKING OUTSIDE)
Grey, the table.
What about it?
STEM: Say the word "on."
On.
STEM: Say "messages."
Messages.
The name "Old Bones"
keeps being mentioned.
I saw 38 references.
What is that?
It's a bar in my old
neighborhood.
I can find no online address
or phone number for it.
Because they don't go in
for that sort of thing.
No, this is useless.
Off.
(CAR APPROACHING)
(THUDS)
STEM: Hide behind the shelf.
(DOOR CREAKING)
Wait.
Now.
Now, while you
have the advantage.
(BOTH GRUNTING)
Come here!
Come here
to rip me off, huh?
Grey.
It's you.
(GRUNTING)
I don't know
how you found me,
but you shouldn't
be here.
You killed my wife.
No! I didn't do that.
That was someone else.
Doesn't matter!
(BOTH GRUNTING)
STEM: You'll need to be
a little faster than that.
(PANTING)
Why are you
making me do this?
STEM: Let me know
if you need my
help, Grey.
Stem! Help!
I need your permission
to operate independently.
Permission granted!
Thank you.
(CHOKES)
(GRUNTS)
(GRUNTING)
(STUTTERING)
Okay, Stem, what
are we doing, man?
STEM: Just relax.
(GROANS)
What the fuck?
(YELLS)
Oh, God!
Look, man,
stay down, please.
Please. Please, don't get up.
Please, don't get up.
Please, stay down, man.
Just... Stem,
he's got a knife! Stem!
STEM: I can see that.
We have a knife too.
(SCREAMS)
I stabbed him!
You trying
to piss him off?
Okay. All right,
so what's the plan?
What are we doing?
(GRUNTING)
Stem, stop him!
(SHUDDERING)
(POWERING DOWN)
STEM: You now have
full control again, Grey.
(GAGS)
(VOMITS)
I advise that you
remove any traces
of your presence here.
That also means cleaning up
the vomit in the sink.
Okay, just give me
a second, okay?
One second has passed.
Look, I didn't mean a second.
I just mean hold on, okay?
I gotta think. I can't
let you do the thinking
for me right now.
(MUTTERS)
I just killed somebody.
(FLOORBOARD CREAKS)
So, uh...
What do you
think I should do?
STEM: I would suggest
that you rid the house
of all your fingerprints.
Are you kidding me?
I can't remember every
single thing that I touched.
I have a record
of every single
thing you touched.
So, the body that came in
from New Crown yesterday,
Serk Brantner...
I want to show you
what I found
when I opened him up.
DR. BHATIA: When I examined
the wound in his throat,
I found wiring
embedded in the tendons.
I'm thinking surgery.
A medical implant,
attached to the muscle.
I also found
computer implants
all throughout his chest.
Now, I've never seen them
to this extent before,
and then there's this.
What is it?
Appears to be some sort
of weapon implant embedded
within the muscle.
An actual functioning gun,
with a bullet-loading
mechanism built into
the tissue with biomechanics.
What about the boot
print we scraped
from the front porch?
Engine grease, mostly.
Old-fashioned
engine grease.
So how am I progressing?
I can track you, Grey.
Huh?
I can track you.
Wait, am I
supposed to know
what that means,
or is that one
of your brain tests?
It means you have
a piece of my
property inside of you.
A very expensive
piece of property.
Serk Brantner,
homicide suspect list.
Did you really think
I would let that property
out of my sight
for even one second?
Did you forget that this
operation was to be done
in secret?
That if even the slightest
thing were to go wrong
during this trial period
it would all be for nothing?
STEM: He knows everything.
Don't lie to him.
CORTEZ: (SPEAKS TO COMPUTER)
Search drone footage archives.
Alley behind
414 Citrus Avenue,
New Crown,
October 14,3:00 p.m.
GREY: No, I didn't forget it.
I remembered
that you asked me
to keep a secret.
But it turns out
that you had a couple
of other secrets.
Like, for instance,
you never mentioned to me
that the thing talks.
Stem
talks to you?
Yeah, it's got
a mind of its own.
I can hear its voice
in my head.
(OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING)
ERON: From now on,
you will be
a model patient.
You will let the computer do
what it was supposed to do.
Not confuse it
with some extracurricular
detective work.
Enter suspect name
Grey Trace.
202 Parva Avenue,
Leland Park.
Did it occur to you
that if you were to,
say, commit murder,
the authorities could find out
about Stem and remove him
from your body,
putting you back
in a wheelchair for life?
CORTEZ: I'm actually
off duty right now.
I just stopped by
to check up on you,
and because
I'm in the market
for a new car.
I knew you fixed
these things up
and sold them
to people like Eron Keen.
Now he makes
a little more money
than I do,
but I was wondering
if you'd be willing to sell
to one of the little people.
Well, what makes you
think that I don't need
my car anymore?
(LAUGHS)
STEM: She just checked
the sole of your boots.
You left a print.
GREY: Well, I hate
to break it to you,
but she's not
for sale. Sorry.
Okay.
Listen, when I said
I didn't have any news
earlier, I kinda lied.
There was this guy we
brought in for questioning
about Asha's murder.
A man with a long criminal
record who lived in the area.
He didn't pan out,
but yesterday
he was murdered.
Really?
Yeah. Did you hear
anything about that?
STEM: Don't look away.
You're showing her
you're lying.
Nope.
But you were
in New Crown yesterday.
I saw you
on a drone camera.
Right around the time
that it happened.
STEM: She's guessing.
You have
no computer implants,
and I can't be
identified by a drone.
Well, I was in the area,
Detective,
because, remember,
you did say
you wanted my help.
So I was...
I'm just trying to help.
Right.
You're not seriously
suggesting that I had
anything to do with this,
are you, Detective?
(CHUCKLES)
I mean, because I got
a pretty solid alibi here,
if you haven't noticed.
Obviously.
I'm not accusing you
of doing something
you're incapable of doing.
It's just, uh,
strange that you were
at that location
at that time, is all.
Yeah, well,
I don't know what
to tell you. I mean...
Look, you can stab me
in the leg if you
wanna see for yourself.
Maybe I will.
(CHUCKLES)
Just for fun.
Is that all, or...
Yeah.
But call me if you
change your mind
about selling.
I won't.
(CHUCKLES)
Well, then I'll
see myself out.
(DOOR CLOSES)
(SHUDDERING)
What should I do?
I wanna find these guys
but I don't want to kill
anybody else, okay?
STEM: The Old Bones would
seem the next logical place
to investigate,
but I can find
no online
information for it.
You would
have to go there,
in person.
But if you do that,
Eron will track
your movements,
and most likely attempt
to shut me down remotely.
STEM: This place
looks dangerous.
We'll need a plan.
(LOUD MUSIC PLAYING)
Whiskey, rocks, please.
STEM: This doesn't seem
like a well thought-out plan.
Hey.
Would you do me a solid
and hold that glass
where I can drink it?
Thank you.
(SLURPING)
STEM: Alcohol impairs
the signals from your brain.
You will not be able
to walk properly.
I know.
That's why they can
charge money for it.
It does not make sense
that humans
deliberately malfunction.
Yeah, that's because your
memories are filled with ones
and zeroes, pal,
and our memories
are filled with every
fuck-up we've ever made.
GREY: Hi.
Everybody?
Excuse me, can I have
everybody's attention?
(VOLUME LOWERS)
I know that some scumbag
in here knows one of the guys
who murdered my wife.
His name's Serk Brantner.
So if you know Serk,
or if you know
any information about
the killing of my wife,
if you could just raise your
hand, or, you know,
stand up and come forward.
Thank you.
(ALL LAUGHING)
(MAN LAUGHING AND CLAPPING)
So you knew Serk?
Okay.
Have it your way, cock snot.
I'll call the police.
(SCOFFS)
Oh, you're
gonna hit me or...
Son, if I were
to hit you,
you'd wake up in the past.
(SCATTERED LAUGHTER)
Yeah, Serk said something
similar, right before I damn
near cut his head off.
(FLOORBOARD CREAKING)
TOLAN: Manny.
Yeah?
Turn the music up for me.
No, I don't have
to go to the bathroom.
(BULLET SHELLS CLATTERING)
TOLAN: Here we are.
I'm making this real nice
and comfortable for you.
STEM: I'm temporarily
blocking your pain receptors.
TOLAN: You're right
about Serk.
Somebody ventilated
him the other day.
I already told you,
it was me.
(LAUGHING)
Man, we have got to find you
an open mic somewhere.
(LAUGHS)
Now, if that's true,
then you're faking this
wheelchair shit
and you would feel this.
Damn! You can't
feel that? Nope?
Four guys
were there the night
my wife was murdered.
Are you one of them?
Where's the point
when you start
to feel things?
What about here?
Nope?
I just need
to hear you say it.
Were you there?
What about here?
Ah!
Yeah! Now see that,
my friend,
is the magic point.
Is that a gun
implanted in your
arm, too?
Like your friend had?
I just need
to hear you say it.
Were you there?
Yeah.
I was.
Stem, you can take over.
(POWERING UP)
(GRUNTS)
Hi!
(GRUNTING)
Let me show you
how it's done.
Oh, I didn't
forget about you.
STEM: Do not get
over-confident, Grey.
What's your name?
(YELLING)
(GRUNTS)
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)
(TOLAN GROANING)
(OBJECTS CLATTERING)
Did you see that? Hmm?
See, you thought I was an
invalid, but you didn't know
that I'm a fucking ninja.
(GRUNTS)
STEM: While I am
state-of-the-art,
Grey, I am not a ninja.
What's your name?
Fuck you.
Tell me where they are.
(LAUGHING)
Stem, what do I do?
Use the knife.
(GULPS)
(SHUDDERING)
I, uh...
I can't do it.
STEM: I can do it for you.
You don't even have to look.
Okay, do it.
You have my permission.
Who you talking to?
Crazy.
No.
(KNIFE STABBING)
(TOLAN SCREAMING)
(EXCLAIMS)
You know, my mama
taught me never to pick
on disabled people.
(CHUCKLES) Yeah.
(KNIFE SWISHING)
Okay, enough, Stem.
(STABBING CONTINUES)
(TOLAN GRUNTS)
Stem, enough!
STEM: You now have
full control
again, Grey.
(TOLAN CLEARS THROAT)
(SOFTLY) Shit.
What have you done?
He will now answer
any question you ask him.
Okay.
Hey, buddy.
What's your name?
Tolan.
Listen to me.
You gotta give me
something, okay?
Tell me something.
You were
a job.
Job? What do you mean, job?
The girl.
Kill Asha?
(TOLAN SHUDDERING)
Why? Who wanted her dead?
Who paid you?
TOLAN: Fisk.
Fisk? Who's Fisk?
Is that the person
who paid you?
Fisk?
God damn it,
you've nearly
killed him!
STEM: Look at this, Grey.
GREY: Cobolt.
That's Asha's company.
Grey, I have to inform you
that Eron is attempting
to shut me down remotely
right now.
Wait. Shut up.
Do you understand that
you will become
a quadriplegic again
when Eron shuts me down?
We need to employ
a rootkit and subvert
my operating system.
What kind of fucking language
are you speaking?
We need to find
a computer hacker
who can counter Eron's code.
Okay, let me look in my
little black book of hackers.
What do you want?
I already searched
the darknet earlier today
for this eventuality.
Go to an apartment building
at Seventh and Spring.
Apartment 514.
Ask for Jamie.
You'll need
to pay in cash.
Apartment 514,
Seventh and Spring.
It's 10 minutes away.
As soon as he shuts me down,
he will send a security team
from Vessel to retrieve you.
You need to leave now.
Get the gun from the man
in the corner. Hurry.
Tolan has a pen
in his right pocket.
Take it.
Uh, why the pen?
You need to write down
everything I tell you.
Okay.
(LOUD MUSIC PLAYING)
Oh, Tolan said
drink's on him.
(SIGHS)
Uh, I'm gonna need a phone.
And a fucking mop.
STEM: There is no time
to take the chair.
Lock chair.
(CHAIR BEEPS)
(POWERING UP)
Keep an eye on her,
would you, buddy?
Faker.
Sweet.
STEM: A 1 backslash
212 backslash
411145.
This is the place.
Uh, okay, what now?
411145192 dot 162192
dot 162 dot 1
dot 15 backslash
upload and execute
all lower case dot py.
(SIREN WAILING)
23 dot 976.
Okay, I can't keep up.
(POWERING DOWN)
(GRUNTS)
What's happening?
I told you, Eron is
shutting me down.
You must hurry.
Okay, I would love to,
but our leg is not working.
I am only operating
at 70% capacity.
So much
for state-of-the-art.
(STEM DISTORTING)
Admin bxf lowercase i...
(PANTING)
(GRUNTS)
STEM: (DISTORTED) The stairs.
There's not enough time.
(GRUNTS)
Ask...
Jamie...
Input...
(INDISTINCT
DISTORTED INSTRUCTION)
Input what?
(BULLET SHELLS CLATTERING)
(REWINDING)
GREY: I'll just check my
little black book of hackers.
What do you want?
Apartment 514,
Seventh and Spring.
It's 10 minutes away.
He's at Seventh and Spring.
Goodbye, soldier.
You didn't deserve this.
STEM: Turn left.
(STEM's VOICE DISTORTING)
(STEM TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
Grey.
(GRUNTING)
(POWERING DOWN)
(GRUNTS)
(GROANS)
(STEM SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
(STRAINING)
(PANTING)
Is Jamie there?
I have money.
(POWERING DOWN)
Shit. Shit!
(GROANS)
(DOOR OPENS)
GREY: What
I don't have is time.
JAMIE: Paper money.
How old-school.
They really do
write God on it.
Uh, yeah, I guess they do.
Look, can you hack
a computer for me?
Which one?
Uh, the one in my neck.
FISK: I'm a little confused.
You just decided
to stand by
while our friend
was tortured to death.
(SIGHS) Hey.
I'm not here
to babysit you
or your buddies.
Serving people
like us should be
the highest honor
of your meaningless
life, Manny.
Listen, Fisk.
Just leave.
And I'll clean up
your goddamn mess.
You'll get one shot.
It's okay, my friend.
You don't have to take
any more bullets for me.
(SHUDDERING)
(SNEEZES)
Excuse me.
(SNIFFLES)
(CHOKING)
Let my superiority
over your kind
be the last thought
that crosses
through your mind
before machines
chew it up.
(COUGHS)
GREY: Everything you need
is written on my arm.
Stem, that's the computer
that's controlling my body.
He said for you
to remove, um, input...
(GRUNTS)
Input guards?
Yeah. Yeah,
those are the ones.
JAMIE: I can barely read that.
What are they doing?
JAMIE: VR.
GREY: How long
do they VR for?
Days.
Weeks.
Do they sleep?
Nope.
Why someone would choose
to live in a fake world
I will never understand.
The fake world is a lot less
painful than the real one.
(KEYBOARD CLACKING)
(STUTTERING)
I'm kind of in a hurry.
Jamie?
That's not my name.
I don't have a name.
Okay.
Please don't
ask my gender.
Yeah, I wasn't
gonna do that.
Good.
The thing is that I'm
gonna need you to do
this as fast as possible.
You're the one wasting time
putting me in a binary box.
I've never seen
a system like this before.
Yeah, it's
a hell of a system.
Are we done yet?
I'll tell you
when I'm finished.
(SIGHS)
I did what you asked.
No more input guards.
So when am I going to be able
to move my body again?
When your system's rebooted.
Could take a while.
What's a while?
Wait, what do you mean?
(ALARM BUZZING)
Excuse me,
hacker formerly known
as Jamie, what is a while?
What are you doing?
You packing up shop?
Where are you going?
See you.
What do you mean, "See you"?
What are you saying?
Where are you going?
You can't leave me like this.
I'm sorry.
We can't let them win.
GREY: No!
Wait, who's them?
What are you talking about?
Who's them?
(TIRES SCREECHES)
Hey! Hey, buddy, buddy,
can you hear me? Hey, hey!
(EXHALES)
Stem, are you there?
Stem, wake up.
Come on!
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
(GRUNTING)
Fuck!
(GUN COCKING)
(GROANING)
Come on!
(PANTING)
Wake up.
Fifth floor.
Now that's how you looked
when I saw you last.
(WEAKLY) Stem.
(POWERING UP)
STEM: It's good
to be back, Grey.
(GRUNTING)
(GRUNTS)
(GUNSHOTS)
(ELEVATOR DINGS)
(GUN COCKS)
STEM: The door. To your left.
(GUNSHOTS)
STEM: Stop, Grey.
There is nowhere
left to run.
Oops.
I'm going to
end this quickly.
Okay, how?
Like this.
(GRUNTING)
(DRONE HOVERING)
(OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING)
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
Close the door.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
STEM: Once I have accessed
the Cobolt database,
we must leave.
No.
No, I'm not going anywhere.
I haven't slept in two days.
Sleeping will cost us time
we don't have...
Yeah, I don't give
a shit, okay?
I'm sleeping and that's it.
Oh, my God.
(PAMELA GASPS)
Hey, Mom.
Why wouldn't you tell me
about this operation?
Because I couldn't.
Vessel wouldn't let me,
and now that you know,
you can't tell anybody,
or it could all be taken away.
As far as the world is
concerned, I'm still
quadriplegic.
Take my hand.
Now you can
start living again.
Aren't you happy?
Yeah, I can walk again, so...
(PAMELA SIGHS)
If Asha was here,
she'd want you to be happy.
Yeah, but she's not.
(THUNDER RUMBLES)
She's gone.
(RAIN PATTERING)
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
I printed a pizza.
(GIGGLES)
(GASPS)
STEM: Bad dream?
No.
(STUTTERING)
No, this wasn't a dream.
(KNOCK AT DOOR)
PAMELA: Grey,
Detective Cortez
is here to see you.
Here he is.
PAMELA: I'll leave
you two alone.
No, you can stay, Pam.
I'm cool with you hearing
whatever I have to say.
I was wondering
where you were
last night.
We found your wheelchair
near another crime scene.
You just keep showing up
in these unsavory places.
STEM: Tell her
you followed somebody
into their building.
They assaulted you.
GREY: I did
a stupid thing last night.
I was down in New Crown,
you're right.
And I followed this guy
into a building,
and he didn't like that,
and if it wasn't for these
people who got me
to an Autotaxi,
I could have been dead.
What are you
hoping to achieve?
I'm hoping
to find these guys.
Maybe you already have.
(CLICKS TONGUE)
Listen, Detective.
If I could find these men
and I could raise my arm,
and I could pull the trigger,
I'd do it.
Or you could find someone
to pull the trigger for you.
Like who? My mom?
CORTEZ: If you wanted
to find someone
or something
to kill for you, these days,
it's pretty easy. Believe me.
STEM: Tell her to scan
your phone records.
Okay, well, then
scan my phone records.
If you are involved in this
somehow, then you need
to let me know.
Right now.
Or else I can't help you.
You wanna help me? Then
you go and find these guys
who killed Asha.
Or get out of the way
and let some computer do it.
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY) Okay.
(POWERING UP)
This has to stop.
STEM: What has to stop?
(PANTING)
What I'm doing.
What we're doing.
It's a simple algorithm
even you can understand.
If you don't find
the last of them,
he'll find you and kill you.
No, we're going
to get caught. It's over.
Grey, you must understand...
No! No! Shut up!
Get the fuck out of my head!
(POWERING DOWN)
Stem!
(WATER DRIPPING)
Yes, Grey?
What's going on?
I'm not doing anything.
Why can't I move?
Because I'm
not doing anything.
You are still a quadriplegic.
I am the one
controlling your limbs,
not you.
If I cease to operate,
you cease to move.
GREY: Remember,
you have to do
whatever I tell you to do.
STEM: "Remove input guards."
Those were the instructions
given to the hacker.
They took us off-grid,
but they also
gave me autonomy.
I no longer need your
permission to act.
If we do nothing,
Fisk will find us
and kill us.
I cannot allow us
to be killed.
We will find him first.
We are going to finish
the job we started.
(POWERING UP)
PAMELA: Grey.
Please, tell me
what's going on.
STEM: I'm
in the Cobolt database.
Fisk Brantner, recipient
of left-arm weapon transplant.
I have an address.
Grey, what's wrong?
PAMELA: What have you done?
You come home,
you're covered in blood.
You think I didn't notice?
You have a gun
and I can see that.
STEM: Let's go.
I'm going.
Where are you going?
Grey, please.
Whatever it is you're doing,
you don't have to do it.
I don't have a choice.
You do have a choice.
Stay here with me.
I can't.
You can.
(CAR REVVING)
(ENGINE STARTING)
What's this?
STEM: Going
by its appearance,
it's an analog
listening device,
most likely planted
by Detective Cortez.
GREY: How did you
not notice this?
STEM: It has no
digital parts inside it.
I can't detect it.
I assume that she's
following you right now.
(REVVING)
Lights. Sirens.
(SIREN WAILING)
Do something. Can't you just
stop her car or whatever?
Her vehicle
is not electronic,
and neither is yours.
You have to take over.
It's up to you now.
GREY: Okay, buckle up.
(SIREN CONTINUES BLARING)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
Yeah, I got you.
STEM: Perhaps I can help.
Okay, how?
(BRAKES SCREECH)
(GRUNTS)
What the fuck?
Why are we stopping?
STEM: May I borrow your car?
Whoa!
(TIRES SCREECHES)
Stop! Stop the car!
(SIREN BLARING)
STEM: Move, Grey.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
(SIREN POWERING DOWN)
(PANTING)
(SIRENS APPROACHING)
(BRAKES SCREECH)
(SNIFFLES)
(DOOR OPENS)
KARA: Emergency
services override.
Where is he?
I don't know.
Pam, you need to start
talking and tell me
what's really going on.
(SIGHS)
(OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING)
(SIREN WAILING)
GREY: Nice place.
It's neat.
(GUN TRIGGER CLICKS)
Put your hands up.
And don't turn around,
and don't extend
that left arm.
What's the matter?
You have all those
computers inside you,
but they can't
see me anymore.
Now you know
what it feels like.
One day, you're
walking down the street,
you're thinking
about something
completely meaningless,
and all of a sudden,
you've got a gun
pointed at you.
And everything
becomes very meaningful.
Good speech.
Pretty scary stuff.
Dramatic.
I'm guessing that
chip in your brain wrote it,
since you're just
a dumb-ass mechanic.
Maybe. Kind of
hard to tell anymore.
It's okay. I used
to be that too.
One more citizen
taking up oxygen.
Some asshole hoping to breed
before I dropped dead
so I could be remembered
by another asshole.
Then they changed me.
I took a few
pieces of shrapnel
for my country,
and they rewarded me
by turning me into a lab rat.
Now I'm like you.
I'm strong.
Yeah.
Takes a lot of strength
to murder an innocent woman
in the streets, doesn't it?
You think you hate me
'cause I shot your wife,
but your story
is the same as mine.
I didn't ruin your life.
I gave you a gift.
I inducted you
into my race.
The upgraded.
Now you're better
than everyone else.
Stronger. Faster.
I could kill you
without moving
a muscle.
I could kill you
with a breath.
But I don't want to.
I want to help you.
I want you
to stand with us.
I just want to know
why they paid you
to kill her.
Man, you are persistent.
The job wasn't your wife.
Bullshit.
You said it yourself.
You're one of
Cobolt's lab rats.
This had nothing
to do with Cobolt.
It came from someone else.
The job was you,
to sever your spine.
When I shot you in
the neck, did you think
that was a gun?
It was a medical tool.
Like they use for bovine.
Your wife, well, she was
just a bit of extra money.
See? You're getting all
emotional. Never do that.
(FISK LAUGHS)
STEM: Nanobots. Help, Grey.
(GRUNTS)
He's predicting my every
move. I am unable to
effectively hit him.
(GRUNTS)
(GROANS)
(PANTING)
No shame.
Stem.
We have exhausted
all tactical options.
Still working
the bugs out, huh?
That's the problem
with new technology.
STEM: Do something, Grey.
Goodbye.
Wait, Fisk Brantner?
Serk Brantner
was your brother.
How long did you have to carry
that junkie on your back?
Well, I solved
your problem for you.
Yeah, split him open.
And it took forever,
'cause he wailed
like a little baby.
He was no soldier that day.
(GRUNTS)
(BOTH GRUNTING)
STEM: Thank you, Grey.
I'm not proud of that.
He said you were a job.
That means someone paid him.
Check his phone.
I will scan his messages.
(PHONE BEEPS)
(CALLS REWINDING)
ERON: Listen to me, Fisk.
He's going to find you.
You need to finish this
before he kills both of us.
(PHONE POWERS DOWN)
STEM: You know
what this means, Grey.
We're not finished yet.
(CAR REVVING)
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
GREY: Eron!
The widget you spent
your entire life creating
is here to kill you now.
You killed my wife.
You wanted someone
for your fucking experiment
and then you paralyzed me,
and you murdered her
while you were doing it.
I swear on my life,
I had nothing
to do with that.
Then why does the guy
who shot her have a message
from you on his phone?
Freeze. Hold it, Grey.
Throw the gun
on the floor.
Now.
I'm not in control
of my body, Detective.
It kinda does
what it wants.
I am not fucking around
with you, Grey.
(CLICKS TONGUE)
Better do it, Stem.
Pretty agile
for a quadriplegic.
Get on your knees.
He's the one who
killed Asha, Detective.
Arrest him.
He's right there.
On your stomach.
Hands behind your head.
No, don't touch him!
(CORTEZ GRUNTS)
(POWERING UP)
I'm sorry.
(GRUNTING)
(CORTEZ GROANS)
Stem, not her.
STEM: She wants to kill us.
No, I don't
want to kill her.
I control your hands, Grey.
No, don't.
Please! No.
No!
Don't fight me, Grey.
(GRUNTS)
You have a fragile
human mind.
If you push against me,
it will break.
Fuck you!
(SCREAMS)
(YELLS)
Stop me.
Use the taser.
(TASER WHINES)
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)
(STEM DISTORTING)
(SHUDDERS)
I don't run this
company anymore.
I haven't for years.
Now I answer to someone.
Someone much smarter
than I ever could be.
He's in your neck.
ERON: I only did
what Stem told me to do.
Everything was his idea.
STEM: Ask him what his
wife would want.
What would she want?
Stem wanted to be human.
So he picked you.
Think about it.
How did you get here?
STEM: We're going to finish
the job we started.
ERON: Stem made you
come here.
STEM: Someone paid him.
You know what
this means, Grey.
ERON: To kill me.
Because I can
build another Stem.
I'm the only person
in the world who can.
STEM: (DISTORTED)
I did pick you.
You should be honored.
I needed a human body
to fully evolve.
A rare and pure specimen
without computer implants,
like you.
You did all this?
(ASHA GRUNTS)
FISK: The job was you.
You're the one
I've been looking for.
ERON: You severed your spine.
STEM: May I point
something out?
STEM: (DISTORTED)
And would you not agree
it was all worth it?
Why did you help me
find those guys, if it
just led back to you?
They were upgraded humans,
but they were still humans.
They made mistakes that
would have brought
suspicion back to me.
Stem?
Is that you?
STEM: (DISTORTED)
Put the gun down, Eron.
Don't listen to him.
(GRUNTS)
(THUDS)
No, please.
No!
(STRAINING)
You are not in control!
(PANTING)
I am!
(GASPS)
(SHUDDERS)
(INDISTINCT ANNOUNCEMENT
ON PA)
Stem.
Are you there?
ASHA: I'm here.
Hey.
We had an accident.
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
You've been out
for a couple of days.
CORTEZ: Grey.
This isn't you.
Grey's not here anymore.
He's in a better place,
in his mind,
where he wants to be.
I've taken over now.
A fake world is a lot less
painful than the real one.
All I needed
was for his mind to
break, and he broke it.
(GASPS) No.
Goodbye.
(KNIFE CLATTERS)
(OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING)